<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[xavijam]]></title>
  <link href="http://xavij.am/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://xavij.am/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-28T22:54:41+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://xavij.am/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[xavijam]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[xavijam@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five years at Vizzuality]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2014/01/27/Five-years-at-Vizzuality/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-27T09:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2014/01/27/Five-years-at-Vizzuality</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>
      There is no a better moment to start again with my blog, celebrating my fifth anniversary at Vizzuality. After my first years in this wadusfera I can only say thanks to the team and the people who have worked here.
      <br/><br/>
      <img title="some-of-the-team" alt="some-of-the-team" src="http://xavij.am/assets/img/posts/five-years-vizzuality/ha.jpg" />
      <br/>
      I could say we have done things (some we can&#8217;t mention) that we are proud. Lot of projects, with great companies, things that mattered. But this adventure hasn&#8217;t finished and we are ready for new opportunities, and this year is gonna be special.
      <br/><br/>
      I usually like to remember that we were 5 years ago working in a small room in <a href="https://maps.google.com/?q=calle%20angosta%20de%20los%20mancebos,%20madrid">La Latina</a>, tons of dreams, and today I keep them present. If someone asks me about my future, I&#8217;d say the same as before. Keeping the feeling what I do is important.
      <br/><br/>
      My gift for this birthday is a <a href="http://xavij.am/luisoundsystem">small audio player</a><sup>1</sup><sup>2</sup>, using <a href="http://twitter.com/luisico">@luisico</a>&#8217;s sounds playing FIFA :D. If you know him you, you will know how expressive he is. Thanks to all the team for the recordings, to <a href="http://twitter.com/ferdev">@ferdev</a> for splitting the audio files into separate tracks and finally to <a href="http://twitter.com/damagedgoods">@damagedgoods</a> for designing something for this purpose :).
      <br/><br/>
      So, I hope I finish my website soon, and later a visualization I&#8217;ve been developing lately.
      Writing a post every two weeks, &#8230; Let&#8217;s see if it is possible.
      <br/><br/>
      New year, new purposes.
      <br/><br/><br/>
      <i><sup>1</sup> My favorite luisico sound is <a href="http://xavij.am/luisoundsystem/#/claclaclaclaclaclacla">this</a>.</i>
      <br/>
      <i><sup>2</sup> Sorry, only HTML5 browsers, problems under iOS :(.</i>
    </p>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CartoDB ♥ Idealista]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2012/08/16/cartodb-idealista/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-16T09:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2012/08/16/cartodb-idealista</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>
      Everybody has looked for a house at some point in their lives, and it&#8217;s not an easy job. Some months ago was my turn, and I dove into one of the most important real estate portals in Spain called <a href="http://www.idealista.com" target="_blank">Idealista</a>. Really simple and easy to find a house or flat that fits for you. But (there is always a but) I realized they don&#8217;t use any kind of maps to represent the districts and neighborhoods, in fact, they use map images.
      <br/><br/>
      <a href="http://www.idealista.com/alquiler-viviendas/madrid/arganzuela/mapa" target="_blank"><img title="idealista-map" alt="idealista-map" src="http://xavij.am/assets/img/posts/cartodb-idealista/idealista.jpg" /></a>
      <br/>
      Thanks to this I decided to do an alternative using <a href="http://cartodb.com" target="_blank">CartoDB</a> and <a href="http://leaflet.cloudmade.com" target="_blank">Leaflet</a>. Just a simple interactive example of Madrid districts and neighborhoods.
      <br/><br/>
      <a href="http://xavij.am/idealista" target="_blank"><img title="idealista-map" alt="idealista-map" src="http://xavij.am/assets/img/posts/cartodb-idealista/idealista-cartodb.jpg" /></a>
      <br/>
      You can visit the example <a href="http://xavij.am/idealista">here</a>. The code, as always, is in <a href="https://github.com/xavijam/idealista" target="_blank">GitHub</a>, and the data is available in this <a href="https://xavijam.cartodb.com/tables/5275/public" target="_blank">CartoDB table</a> (amount on sale or rent houses are bogus).
      <br/><br/>
      <strong>UPDATED:</strong> Thanks for the corrections <a href="http://twitter.com/javier" target="_blank">@javier</a> :).
    </p>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[After some years, it's time to recap...]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2012/07/31/after-some-years-its-time-to-recap-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-31T08:57:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2012/07/31/after-some-years-its-time-to-recap-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>
      I started in <a href="http://vizzuality.com" target="_blank">Vizzuality</a> several years ago and after some projects done, lot of friends made and many hours worked, it&#8217;s time to recap and look back to understand what we have achieved.
      <br/><br/>
      <a href="http://xavij.am/vizzuality-timeline"><img src="http://xavij.am/assets/img/posts/vizzuality-timeline/vizzuality-timeline.jpg" title="vizzuality-timeline" alt="vizzuality-timeline" /></a>
      <br/>
      I&#8217;ve simply <strike>followed</strike> copied the Facebook timeline trend to visualize some of the most important days in this group of friends (still adding days, not finished!).
      <br/><br/>
      I&#8217;ve used <a href="http://cartodb.com">CartoDB</a> as backend, the code is in <a href="https://github.com/xavijam/vizzuality-timeline">GitHub</a> and you can see it <a href="http://xavij.am/vizzuality-timeline">here</a>.
      <br/><br/>
      Thank all the vizz crew for put up with me everyday, and also, thanks to all the people who helped us and now they aren&#8217;t here, my best wishes in their new adventures.
    </p>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I need you!]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2012/04/03/i-need-you/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-03T08:57:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2012/04/03/i-need-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>
      Run out of fuel. Those are the perfect words to explain what&#8217;s going on with <a href="http://libr.in" title="Librin">libr.in</a>. Several months ago I started a great personal project, with lot of illusion, energies and hopes. Today this project is really advanced, but only in the programming part, almost with the 72% of the job done.
      <br /><br />
      But I have a problem with the design, and why?, easy, because I&#8217;m not a designer, and I like it so much that I can&#8217;t <strike>copy</strike> <strong>create</strong> a design that fits my expectations. So I would like to share this project with someone who wants to make it a great and funny job.
      <br /><br />
      <strong>What can I offer?</strong>
      <br /><br />
      No money, it will be an open source project when it is ready, so if you look for that, don&#8217;t continue reading. I can offer the half of the project, fun time working with someone peculiar, create a useful web tool, &#8230;
      <br /><br />
      <strong>Are there any conditions?</strong>
      <br /><br />
      No, there aren&#8217;t. However my spoken languages are english and spanish. And I would like to release the project before end of May (I&#8217;m a dreamer), so if you are busy the next two months&#8230;
      <br /><br />
      This is not a hiring process, or something similar, there won&#8217;t be money (it has to be clear), I just want to share something I really love and make it real. Actually, I&#8217;m asking for help :) . If you want to know more about libr.in write an email to <a href="mailto:tengoun@libr.in" title="Librin">tengoun@libr.in</a>.
      <br /><br />
      If you find this post via twitter, please RT :). Thanks!
    </p>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'll be at Denver talking about maps + HTML5]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2011/09/12/ill-be-at-denver-talking-about-maps-plus-html5/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-12T10:42:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2011/09/12/ill-be-at-denver-talking-about-maps-plus-html5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>
      Seems like I will be at FOSS4G Denver conference talking about HTML5 for Rich Geospatial applications on the web.
      It will happen on Friday 15th, at 10am. I have to say that my english is not my goal, but I will do my best to do it properly :).
      <br/><br/>
      One more thing! Presentation will be online for everybody the same day after the talk <a href="http://xavijam.github.com/html5-foss4g/" title="html5-foss4g">here</a>.
    </p>
  </div>
  <iframe width="100%" frameborder="0" height="220" src="https://xavijam.cartodb.com/tables/denver/embed_map?scrollwheel=false"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Messy CSS]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2011/08/09/messy-css/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-09T09:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2011/08/09/messy-css</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>Is there anything more annoying than a messy CSS? Probably yes, but why not try to avoid that?.
    I have uploaded a simple presentation talking about that, just a simple way to improve your CSS properties.
    Just take it into account when you compare your CSS with your mates.
    You can read it at <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/xavijam/messy-css" title="messy-css">slideshare</a>.
    </p>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rendering 5000 canvas markers with Leaflet]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2011/06/19/rendering-5000-canvas-markers-with-leaflet/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-19T09:30:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2011/06/19/rendering-5000-canvas-markers-with-leaflet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>
      Thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/jatorre" title="Javier de la Torre">@jatorre</a> I discovered a <a href="http://broady.github.com/Dotter/example.html">great representation of thousand
      of markers using canvas</a> image in Google Maps (using Javascript of course), developed by <a href="http://twitter.com/broady" title="Broady">@broady</a>, a great Google developer.
      <br/><br/>
      It uses Gmaps markers with a simple canvas transformed to image. So I’vedecided to create the same example with Leaflet, with two options:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Rendering points with Leaflet marker (<a href="http://xavijam.github.com/Leaflet-Dotter/?markers=true" title="leaflet-dotter">go</a>).</li>
      <li>Rendering points with a custom own marker (<a herf="http://xavijam.github.com/Leaflet-Dotter/" title="leaflet-dotter">go!</a>).</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      From my point of view the difference is sensible using own marker than Leaflet marker.
      As always, the source is available on <a href="https://github.com/xavijam/Leaflet-Dotter" title="GitHub">GitHub</a>.
      <br/><br/>
      Also, if you want to compare deeply, I made one week ago the same experiment with <a herf="http://xavijam.github.com/Gmaps-Dotter/" title="GMaps">GMaps</a>) + custom Gmaps OverlayView.
    </p>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First steps with Leaflet: CustomMarker with canvas and geolocation]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2011/06/11/first-steps-with-leaflet-custommarker-with-canvas-and-geolocation/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-11T10:47:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2011/06/11/first-steps-with-leaflet-custommarker-with-canvas-and-geolocation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>Several moths ago I wanted to create a working example using W3C geolocation and a custom marker (similar to there is in the iphone maps application) in Google Maps v3.
    But these days has appeared <a href="http://leafletjs.com/" title="Leaflet">Leaflet</a>, a new lightweight JavaScript library for making tile-based interactive maps, and I&#8217;ve decided to give it a try. My first approach has consisted of:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>A custom marker made with Canvas.</li>
      <li>Canvas animation in the marker (probably too heavy for the CPU, but it&#8217;s a test).</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Just click in the image to try it (Pss, let me to know your position :) ). If you want to download the code, it&#8217;s in <a href="https://github.com/xavijam/geolocate-point" title="GitHub">github</a>. I&#8217;ve found two things really weird related to geolocation:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Safari (5.0.5) doesn&#8217;t return anything in geolocation, it gets an error :S.</li>
      <li>Firefox can give you more information than other browser (city, country, street, number,&#8230;), <a href="http://davidwalsh.name/dw-content/geolocation.php" title="geo">try it with your browser</a>.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Leaflet is continually improving the library, although there are some features under developement, you can find a lot of examples to start using it.</p>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
