<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | xavijam]]></title>
  <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://xavij.am/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-30T00:46:41+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://xavij.am/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[xavijam]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[xavijam@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I need you!]]></title>
    <link href="http://xavij.am/blog/2012/04/03/i-need-you/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-03T08:57:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://xavij.am/blog/2012/04/03/i-need-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="columns">
  <div class="columns-content">
    <p>
      Run out of fuel. Those are the perfect words to explain what's going on with <a href="http://libr.in" title="Librin">libr.in</a>. Several months ago I started a great personal project, with lot of illusion, energies and hopes. Today this project is really advanced, but only in the programming part, almost with the 72% of the job done.
      <br /><br />
      But I have a problem with the design, and why?, easy, because I'm not a designer, and I like it so much that I can't <strike>copy</strike> <strong>create</strong> a design that fits my expectations. So I would like to share this project with someone who wants to make it a great and funny job.
      <br /><br />
      <strong>What can I offer?</strong>
      <br /><br />
      No money, it will be an open source project when it is ready, so if you look for that, don't continue reading. I can offer the half of the project, fun time working with someone peculiar, create a useful web tool, ...
      <br /><br />
      <strong>Are there any conditions?</strong>
      <br /><br />
      No, there aren't. However my spoken languages are english and spanish. And I would like to release the project before end of May (I'm a dreamer), so if you are busy the next two months...
      <br /><br />
      This is not a hiring process, or something similar, there won't be money (it has to be clear), I just want to share something I really love and make it real. Actually, I'm asking for help :) . If you want to know more about libr.in write an email to <a href="mailto:tengoun@libr.in" title="Librin">tengoun@libr.in</a>.
      <br /><br />
      If you find this post via twitter, please RT :). Thanks!
    </p>
  </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>